<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Zealand on Arjen&#39;s travels</title>
    <link>https://www.arjen.eu/countries/new-zealand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Zealand on Arjen&#39;s travels</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 05:03:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.arjen.eu/countries/new-zealand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Top of the world!</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/top-of-the-world</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 05:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/top-of-the-world</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Kaikoura I went to pick up Kelsey again. She had spent her time at a farm in the southern part of the island, doing some work there. I stayed with her there during her last two days, pretty much watching other people do work and realizing I really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do any work on a farm. It&amp;rsquo;s not even the work that bothered me, but you had to get up so early…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to go to the North Island after this, and that&amp;rsquo;s what we were going to do. However, that was also still several days of driving, so we&amp;rsquo;d planned on an interesting stop on the way. Mount Cook, the highest mountain of New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LakePukaki.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Lake Pukaki&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LakePukaki-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Lake Pukaki&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Cook is located pretty much in the middle of the island, and is part of the Southern Alps that I&amp;rsquo;d traveled through a couple of times now. To reach it however you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to go into the alps, but instead there&amp;rsquo;s a nice road leading there that goes along Lake Pukaki while offering a first view of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon our arrival after a long day of driving we went to one of the campsites, and explored some of the paths around there. This was pretty nice, and the paths had some interesting information concerning the history of the region as far as it concerned people climbing Mount Cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/Glacier.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Glacier near Mount Cook&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/Glacier-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Glacier near Mount Cook&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day started out cloudy, not exactly what you want when you wish to view a mountain. So, in the morning we went into the township where we explored the Sir Edmund Hillary Center. As the first person to climb to the top of Mount Everest he is probably the second best-known person from New Zealand. After Peter Jackson…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/MountCook.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Mount Cook&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/MountCook-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Mount Cook&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we explored this center dedicated to his exploits for a while until we decided to go outside again. According to the weather predictions it was supposed to clear up in a couple of hours, which meant we could do a couple of the tracks that should give us a good view and hope for the best. Walking around we saw some beautiful sights, but it was still a long time before the clouds broke apart. When that happened though we were in a beautiful location with a good view of the mountain. And that wonderful view was totally worth the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t really more to say about this visit. After enjoying the sight for a while longer we eventually got back into the car to start driving in the direction of Picton again. There we would take the ferry to Wellington and so enter the North Island. But the North Island will be discussed in future posts, so for now just enjoy the photos of Mount Cook and surroundings below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale watching in Kaikoura</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/whale-watching-in-kaikoura</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 06:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/whale-watching-in-kaikoura</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of those things you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to do when visiting New Zealand is to go whale watching. Of course, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to, but it is an interesting experience nonetheless and the best place to do it is Kaikoura. So, that was my next stop after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/12/camping-in-abel-tasman/&#34; title=&#34;Camping in Abel Tasman&#34;&gt;Abel Tasman&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go alone either, as Laura decided to come along before she was going to visit the North Island. Jeroen decided to go there immediately, so it was just the two of us. I&amp;rsquo;d gone here before with Kelsey, but at that time the weather was bad enough that no tours were going, this time I was more lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t actually much to say about this, as whale watching in this case consisted of getting in an airplane and viewing these big animals from the sea, going low enough that we had a good view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/nE6IeUj7uJU&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Abel Tasman</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/camping-in-abel-tasman</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 04:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/camping-in-abel-tasman</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As explained in my post about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/11/fact-of-the-day-glaciers-are-cold/&#34; title=&#34;Fact of the day: Glaciers are cold&#34;&gt;the glaciers&lt;/a&gt;, I met a couple of people there who were willing to join me in doing the Abel Tasman coastal track. So, after we had finished doing what we wanted to do at the glaciers, Jeroen, Laura, and I got into my car and drove North.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/Punakaiki.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Pancake rocks at Punakaiki&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/Punakaiki-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Pancake rocks at Punakaiki&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first part of the trip however, the weather from the glaciers seemed to have followed us and we spent that time in the rain. Luckily, it was sunny when we arrived at the first place we wanted to visit, Punakaiki. I&amp;rsquo;d been here briefly before with Kelsey as the bus we took to Greymouth when we were going to take the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/2012/03/24/the-tranzalpine-experience/&#34; title=&#34;The TranzAlpine experience&#34;&gt;TranzAlpine express&lt;/a&gt; stopped there, but then we had only 20 minutes to view these pancake rocks. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t nearly enough time, even though it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty small place. So, what are these pancake rocks? Actually, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to really explain it as the picture does a good job at showing it. It&amp;rsquo;s a coastal area where all the rocks show clear layers, and has some other interesting features like blowholes and a surge pool. A nice place to stop if you&amp;rsquo;re in the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/TeWaikoropupuSprings.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Te Waikoropupu Springs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/TeWaikoropupuSprings-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Te Waikoropupu Springs&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our stop at Punakaiki we moved on again, heading for the Abel Tasman region, where we arrived at our hostel quite late after having to drive through a pass similar to the Haast pass I&amp;rsquo;d gone through on the way there. So, our first step the next day was to arrange things for our trip through the park, which we were going to do with a tent. So, after arranging a tent and the passes for the walk we then decided to go for a drive into the park first. There were plenty of good places to visit that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see during the actual trekking. So, on this day we visited the Grove Scenic Reserve, the Labyrinth Rocks Park, and the Te Waikoropupu Springs. Of these I would definitely recommend visiting the springs, but don&amp;rsquo;t waste your time on the labyrinth. The most interesting thing about that was probably how somebody had spread out a whole bunch of toys across the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Springs however were truly beautiful. Visitors aren&amp;rsquo;t actually allowed to touch the water though, as these springs are the purest fresh water springs in the world. Only the water underneath the Ross Ice Shelf is known to be clearer. Which already says quite a bit about it. Coupled with the beautiful surroundings, I for one enjoyed my visit there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/StartOfBoatTrip.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Start of the Water Taxi Trip&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/StartOfBoatTrip-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Start of the Water Taxi Trip&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning however, it was time for the three of us to go trekking. Our plan was to be dropped of at the end, and then walk back to the start. For this we&amp;rsquo;d booked places on a water taxi, and so we could enjoy the park from the water as well. The water taxi was pretty quick however, so after a short time we&amp;rsquo;d arrived at the beach that would be the start of our journey. As it happens, there are a number of places on the Abel Tasman Coastal Track that can only be crossed a couple of hours either side of low tide. And the first of these was less than an hour from our starting position. As it was still early, and we therefore had about 3 hours before we could cross that we spent this time wisely by enjoying the sun on the beach. Alas, my sunscreen turned out not to be strong enough, so this would end up having some unfortunate consequences later on. At the time though, it was very enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LowTideCrossingJeroen.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Low tide crossing, Jeroen&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LowTideCrossingJeroen-225x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Low tide crossing, Jeroen&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LowTideCrossing.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Low tide crossing, Laura and I&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LowTideCrossing-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Low tide crossing, Laura and I&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After enjoying the sun for a time, we then started walking again. It was an enjoyable time, with perfect sunny weather. The crossings themselves were even at low tide still watery though, so a fair part of this was walked barefoot. So, eventually we reached our first campsite, where with my extensive knowledge of camping I wisely left the setting up of the tent to the people actually familiar with it, helping where I could of course. Unfortunately, by this time it became quite clear that I was burned pretty badly, which didn&amp;rsquo;t make for either pleasant sleeping in the tent, or carrying a heavy backpack. Laura suffered from the same affliction, but Jeroen seemed to have spent enough time on the beaches in Australia that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t bothered at all. Lucky bastard&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/ViewOfBay.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Anchorage Bay&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/ViewOfBay-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Anchorage Bay&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we had an early start, and were greeted with a cloudy sky. This actually made the walk more pleasant, and as we once again walked through various bays as well as seeing a fair number of waterfalls and other beautiful pieces of nature. This time too, there was a tidal crossing at the very end of our walk that day and so we had to spent more time on the beach waiting for it. A truly horrible experience of course, especially as the sun had made a reappearance by that time. For this crossing we could&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to take the high water route, which would add a mere 1.5 hours to the walk, but we decided to tough it out on the beach instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/EndOfTrack.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;End Of Track&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/EndOfTrack-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;End Of Track&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we spent at Anchorage, the end point for everyone who does a day trip, meaning it was quite busy, but also that the next day wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be very hard. After talking to the DOC ranger at the site we decided to do some short walks that evening, and even visit a small cave of glow worms. The next day was a pretty easy walk back to the start of the track. Flat and short, but because of the burns it wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as pleasant or easy as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked. Still, all in all the Abel Tasman Coastal Track was a really nice walk, and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have done it in such nice company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fact of the day: Glaciers are cold</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/fact-of-the-day-glaciers-are-cold</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 06:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/fact-of-the-day-glaciers-are-cold</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;19-01-2012 until 21-01-2012&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about glaciers. On the South Island the two most famous and accessible glaciers are the Fox and Franz Josef glaciers. As I already had my car and they are located about 20 km from each other it was easy to visit both before I made up my mind about which one I was actually going to visit. Yes, unfortunately this was an I as Kelsey was not with me for this part of my trip.
Both of the glaciers are on the west coast, which is on the other side of the southern alps from basically every other interesting thing in the country. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that great? And with only a three passes through the Southern Alps that means there is a lot of driving to do to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LakeHawea.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Lake Hawea&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/LakeHawea-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Lake Hawea&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My starting point for going there was Lake Hawea, a beautiful lake about 30 kilometers north of Wanaka. I spent the night there at a really good DOC campsite, and could enjoy a morning swim when I got up.&lt;br /&gt;
After this nice swim it then naturally became time to get in the car and drive to the glaciers. This road went past Lake Wanaka, and then into the mountains, following the Haast pass highway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/SouthernAlps.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Southern Alps&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/SouthernAlps-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Southern Alps&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I have to admit that as this was my first time driving in the mountains there were some moments where I had to pay very good attention. It was also the first time I saw slow down ramps, which only purpose was to allow you to slow down after you lost control of your car. No, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to use them. The scenery was amazing though, and I made frequent stops at places like the Blue Pools and a fair number of waterfalls. The experience was improved quite a bit by the great weather during the drive as well. More photos from the drive are in the gallery at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fox-glacier:7ace1cafabde62ba5c5a64f84cc17bc8&#34;&gt;Fox Glacier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FoxGlacier.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Fox Glacier&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FoxGlacier-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fox Glacier&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after a long day of driving I ended up at the Fox Glacier. Unfortunately, the sun doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to like the glaciers so the whole visit to the glaciers was done under an overcast sky. Which is probably a good thing once I was walking on top of one. However, we aren&amp;rsquo;t that far yet. Having just arrived, it was a bit late and I decided to wait until the next day for my visit.
So, I found a place to stay in the Fox Glacier township (population: very few) and went out to the glacier the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FoxGlacierStream.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Stream at Fox Glacier&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FoxGlacierStream-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Stream at Fox Glacier&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the glacier is pretty deceptive, even in the photos it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how big it actually is. As you can go only so far by car, it&amp;rsquo;s about half an hour walk to the glacier itself, where you follow the stream/river that flows from it. A river that at this time was calm and small, but had enough potential for danger that DOC rangers would stake out a path each morning, determining how close people would be allowed to get to the glacier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was an impressive sight, and there were plenty of walks around to admire the view. Of course, while every couple of years the glacier seems to switch between shrinking and growing it has shrunk a lot since it was first discovered. About a hundred years ago it reached almost to the carpark, and during the glacial periods it tended to reach until deep in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;franz-josef-glacier:7ace1cafabde62ba5c5a64f84cc17bc8&#34;&gt;Franz Josef Glacier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FranzJosefGlacier.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Franz Josef Glacier&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/FranzJosefGlacier-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Franz Josef Glacier&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Fox glacier wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one in town and before deciding which of the two I was going to walk on (only possible with expensive tours) I wanted to see both. So, I left the glacier behind and headed for the Franz Josef Glacier about half an hour north of the township.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the township I also picked up a couple of French hitchhikers, Noah and Julie, who I joined in a visit to the hot pools in the Franz Josef township (population: just as few). The hot pools were pretty relaxing after a day of walking through the sometimes rainy, sometimes just cloudy environment around Fox glacier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/TridentFalls.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Trident Falls&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/TridentFalls-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Trident Falls&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, they also decided to go to the camping I wanted to go, and we agreed to go visit the Franz Josef glacier together in the morning. Again, this included a pretty long walk to get there, but it was immediately clear this was the more impressive glacier. It seems to be a lot higher, even just the parts you can see, so I decided that this was the one I would climb. That would have to wait until the next day though. Because for this day I&amp;rsquo;d had enough of the clouds and nearly constant rain. I wanted to see some sun.
That took just a 30 minute drive to the coast, where I would then take a nice walk, before driving back into the clouds. It&amp;rsquo;s really strange how the glaciers were always covered in clouds, but the area around it could still be so nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the next it was time to do the whole ice walking thing, and this was really impressive. Actually walking on the ice gave a really good idea of how big it was. In the pictures you can&amp;rsquo;t even see half of the glaciers, as most of it is in behind the highest visible point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/OnFranzJosef.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;On Franz Josef&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/OnFranzJosef-225x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;On Franz Josef&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that we walked there, aside from being physically impossible and dangerous, it&amp;rsquo;s also too far away. The only way to get there was by helicopter, which was a trip I didn&amp;rsquo;t do. Walking for a whole day over the ice is much more fun than just 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again when trying to write about something as impressive as this, I can&amp;rsquo;t think of any words that would do it justice. So, instead you&amp;rsquo;ll have to be satisfied with a whole bunch of pictures showing us walking over and through kilometers of ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this tour I also met two other people; Jeroen, from Rotterdam in the Netherlands, and Laura, from England. After the tour I went with the two of them to the hot pools again, it was part of the tour, and we decided that we would go to the Abel Tasman national park together. But that story will be told in another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving through the Catlins</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/driving-through-the-catlins</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 02:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/06/driving-through-the-catlins</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Catlins are an area stretching pretty much between Dunedin and Invercargill, and is supposed to be one of the most beautiful areas to travel through in New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, by now I&amp;rsquo;ve come to suspect that pretty much every area in the country is described as that, and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say if those claims are true because it&amp;rsquo;s all very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the Catlins are best travelled by car as that gives you the time to stop where you want and just take your time admiring the scenery without being on a specific schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/MoerakiBoulders.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Moeraki Boulders&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/MoerakiBoulders-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Moeraki Boulders&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens I had bought a car in Christchurch, the reason we went there on the TranzAlpine express, so the Catlins were an excellent way to test the car and get used to driving in New Zealand. And in general actually. Driving south from Christchurch, we first stopped at Moeraki to have a look at the boulders there. These apparently famous boulders are round. They move very slowly (centimeters per year slowly) from the sea onto the beach. As spheres sometimes over 2 meters in diameter that makes them pretty impressive to look at.     Unfortunately, the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as good as we would have liked so we didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/NuggetPoint.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Nugget Point&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/NuggetPoint-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Nugget Point&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the boulders we moved slowly further south until we reached some beaches with unlikely names such as Shag point, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t long after that before we reached the Catlins, where our first stop was the lighthouse at Nugget Point. The lighthouse itself is just another lighthouse, but the area it stands on is impressive. High cliffs with rocks or beaches all around. It was pretty fun to walk around there. This was also the last visit of the day as after that we went to look for a camping place, which we found next to another nice beach. All in all, with also some decent weather this was a pretty good start for our visit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/PurakaunuiFalls.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Purakaunui Falls&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/PurakaunuiFalls-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Purakaunui Falls&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we started out with a visit to Jack&amp;rsquo;s Blowhole. Something that sounds a lot more impressive than it actually is. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy the walk there, but with a name like that I expected a bit more than a hidden opening to the sea where water streamed in. Water blowing into the air was pretty much what I expected, but the most you got there was the sound of the water crashing into the walls of the hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this visit we moved more inland again, and arrived at the Purakaunui Falls, a wide and stepped waterfall. This was a pretty impressive sight, and like in most places on the South Island there weren&amp;rsquo;t many people around, meaning it was a easy to take the time and enjoy the view. Purakaunui Falls was followed by a visit to the equally impressive McLean Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather turned bad again in the evening though, as we went to camp at the holiday park in Curio Bay. A place where a lot of fauna is around, especially dolphins and penguins. Due to the rain we never spotted any of the dolphins unfortunately, but while walking across the park during a dry spell we were pleasantly surprised by a penguin with the same idea. Later on I would even hear stories of people who found penguins just chilling out in front of their tent, but encountering one walking around the park was already quite nice. We would also end up visiting the nesting place for these penguins, although there were warnings not to get between the parents coming from the sea and their young as that might scare the parents off and end up in the young dying. Something nobody wants to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/E7nbg_sbylI&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we were going to visit something different, the Cathedral caves. These caves can only be visited for a short time during the low tide. Getting there required walking over the beach, and as we were a bit late that meant getting our feet wet. So, I took off my shoes, not having thought to wear something more suitable, and because this ended up with very dirty feet I would eventually decide to walk back on my bare feet as well. A bit of do like the natives do thing. Of course, this was over a gravel path and I can definitely recommend anyone not to do something as silly as that. It hurts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/CathedralCaves.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Cathedral Caves&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/06/CathedralCaves-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cathedral Caves&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the caves though. They are really beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s dark inside, naturally, but when using a flashlight or even just the flash of the camera you can see there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of colored stone. The name is pretty well chosen, as the height and sheer size of the main cave has pretty much the same feeling as being in a cathedral. Aside from the religious part of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caves were followed by a trip to Slope Point, the most southern point of the South Island, but because of my earlier visit to Stewart Island not the most southern point I&amp;rsquo;ve visited. Still nice to have been there and a good place to end our visit to the Catlins. On the way there, we also found the New Zealand Niagara Falls. Having seen the original, I was able to compare them, and I must say that with an incredible height of almost 20 cm these were almost as impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos of this, and other views in the Catlins can be viewed in the gallery below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The TranzAlpine experience</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/03/the-tranzalpine-experience</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 05:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/03/the-tranzalpine-experience</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of January Kelsey and I ended up in Greymouth, a small city on the west coast of the South Island. Actually, we came here on purpose as we wanted to go Christchurch as that was the place where I wanted to look for (and ended up buying) a car. So, why go to the other side of the country for that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/03/iPhoto.png&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;TranzAlpine Express route&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/03/iPhoto-300x278.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;TranzAlpine Express route&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is pretty simple actually. While New Zealand appears to have mostly given up on railroads, there are a couple of lines left, and the most famous and beautiful of these is the TranzAlpine express which is a over 4 hour journey from Greymouth to Christchurch that goes through the Southern Alps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that was the plan. To go from Greymouth to Christchurch by way of one of the most beautiful train rides in the world. This train goes once a day, starting in Christchurch early in the morning and starting its return around a quarter to two in the afternoon. This meant we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to hurry and first had a chance to enjoy our stay in Greymouth. Or well, enjoy it as far as possible because to be honest I found Greymouth a pretty boring place.&lt;br /&gt;
The trainride was really worth it though. The scenery was improved by good, but not great, weather leading to a lot of clouds interspersed with blue sky, and the train had a couple of viewing places so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to take the photo&amp;rsquo;s through the glass in the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I could do my best to describe how amazing the views were and how beautiful it all looked, I think the best way to show it is by actually showing it, so I would suggest just clicking on the photos below the post to get a good impression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity and water are your friends</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/02/gravity-and-water-are-your-friends</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 05:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/02/gravity-and-water-are-your-friends</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, as promised, the first post detailing some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, all the stuff my mom didn&amp;rsquo;t want to know about in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bungy-jump:5151a0c9240b0c3bf933cf28dbb3bafa&#34;&gt;Bungy Jump&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Bungy-Jump-Kawarua-Bride-08.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Bungy Jump Kawarua Bridge&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Bungy-Jump-Kawarua-Bride-08-300x199.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bungy Jump Kawarua Bridge&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bungy jumping was an interesting experience. I did it from the Kawarau bridge near Queenstown which was the first commercial bungy jumping place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangely enough I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really nervous about doing it until I was actually on the ledge and looking down. At that point I did start to question my sanity a bit, after all why did I even want to fall down like that? Sure, it always seemed like the thing to do when I&amp;rsquo;d get to Queenstown, but was it really necessary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really given a choice in the matter once I was up there so I just made the most of it and did a dive that makes it all look a bit better. Besides, Kelsey was there and she&amp;rsquo;d done one so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t look bad :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/kP0NhvXg3Jo&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jet-boat:5151a0c9240b0c3bf933cf28dbb3bafa&#34;&gt;Jet boat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Jetboat-Queenstown-03.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Jetboat Queenstown&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Jetboat-Queenstown-03-300x201.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Jetboat Queenstown&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Queenstown as well, after all it&amp;rsquo;s the place to go to for activities like this, we went on a jet boat. Basically this is a boat that can go in about 5 centimeter deep water and consists mainly of an engine. The ride itself then went through the Shotover river where we went over plenty of shallow water and making 360 degrees turns. Pretty exciting, and fun to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;white-water-rafting:5151a0c9240b0c3bf933cf28dbb3bafa&#34;&gt;White water rafting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Rafting-Queenstown-5.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;White Water Rafting Queenstown&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Rafting-Queenstown-5-300x201.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;White Water Rafting Queenstown&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after the jet boat I went rafting. This also took place on the Shotover river, but on a different part of it. Well, rafting is rafting so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear what went on here. We were first transported to the start of the track in a bus driving on a road that&amp;rsquo;s basically one big disaster waiting to happen but has some great views. Of course, it was pretty cloudy that day so the views were somewhat limited and I also didn&amp;rsquo;t bring my camera so I can&amp;rsquo;t even show the views. Just believe me when I say they looked good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there we all got sorted into rafts, and as usual there was the whole bumping other rafts into the rocks and water fights thing. We could also go out of the raft for a bit to swim through one of the rapids, which was fun in its own way. Luckily we wore wetsuits or it would have been too cold.
The movie embedded below doesn&amp;rsquo;t show my day for the most part, but still gives a good view of what it was like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skydive:5151a0c9240b0c3bf933cf28dbb3bafa&#34;&gt;Skydive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Skydive-Wanaka-064.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Skydive Wanaka&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Skydive-Wanaka-064-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Skydive Wanaka&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highpoint of all these activities was the skydive. I did this in Wanaka because I&amp;rsquo;d heard the view there was the best. It was simply awesome.
For the skydive I was nervous long before I actually got into the little airplane that was going to take me up there. Especially as they were running late so it took some extra time. Anyway, I got really nervous while waiting and during the whole 30 minutes flight I could still feel the butterflies tap-dancing in my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the moment arrived where I actually jumped (with help from the guy attached to my back) out of a perfectly fine airplane from a height of 15.000 feet. The free fall was pretty much one of the best things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever felt. Complete freedom and the wind just rushing past your face. Only enjoying the sights and feelings of that wind. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to describe really, but I can definitely recommend it to everybody. Just thinking about it makes me happy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parachuting the last part was pretty good as well, and gave a better opportunity to enjoy the sights, but it was nothing compared to the free fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/T0uI8Ll0P-M&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;canyoning:5151a0c9240b0c3bf933cf28dbb3bafa&#34;&gt;Canyoning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Canyoning-Wanaka-06745.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Canyoning Wanaka&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Canyoning-Wanaka-06745-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Canyoning Wanaka&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canyoning was another thing I did while I was in Wanaka. What is canyoning? Basically it&amp;rsquo;s moving through a canyon, but in doing so you&amp;rsquo;ll end up doing all kind of fun stuff like abseiling cliffs and waterfalls, sliding through streams, crawling in a lot of places, ziplining, jumping of cliffs and more. It lasted all day, and while I was pretty exhausted in the end I also had a lot of fun. I saw a canyon from a way you usually don&amp;rsquo;t see them, and most importantly did a lot of things I never did before but that turned out to be quite interesting to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the playing with water and gravity I did in all these activities was a lot of fun and I can only recommend everyone to do them. Especially the skydive as that is just too much fun not to do. Except probably when you&amp;rsquo;re afraid of heights and/or flying, it&amp;rsquo;s probably not a very good idea in that case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 days on the South Island</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/02/100-days-on-the-south-island</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 10:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2012/02/100-days-on-the-south-island</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I updated this. A lot has happened since my last real post (not counting the merry christmas one, or actually even including that one) and I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail with all of that as I&amp;rsquo;ll write some separate posts for all of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/southislandpictures.png&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;The places where I’ve take pictures on the South Island&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/southislandpictures-263x300.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The places where I’ve take pictures on the South Island&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking the ferry to the North Island, leaving the South Island behind me. I&amp;rsquo;ll have spent exactly 100 days (give or take an hour) on the South Island, but actually leaving tomorrow isn&amp;rsquo;t because of that number. It just worked out that way.
So, what have I been doing all that time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taken about 5000 pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taken about 30 minutes of video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rented and later bought a car&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drove over 6000 kilometers in my own car&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a bungy jump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a skydive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visited some of the most beautiful places in the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walked 3 of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s Great Walks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fell in love with a wonderful girl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kelsey:230c8bf5dc0a96da5bf7e86382b0da14&#34;&gt;Kelsey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Kelsey-Lai-45.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Kelsey Lai&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Kelsey-Lai-45-225x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kelsey Lai&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last post was from Te Anau, and the most important part of the rest of my story actually starts there as I met a lovely girl there. I originally met Kelsey in Invercargill after I got back from my trip to Stewart Island, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until we met again in Te Anau that we got together, spent time together and eventually fell in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelsey is from Hong Kong and has been in New Zealand since December 2010, working and traveling in the South Island. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to put everything about her into words that I can post on a blog though, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to do that. I wanted to write a lot more about her, but everything I try to say seems like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do her justice, so I guess you&amp;rsquo;re all out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-car:230c8bf5dc0a96da5bf7e86382b0da14&#34;&gt;A car&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Catlins-7870.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;My car&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2012/02/Catlins-7870-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;My car&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a car, a Nissan Avenir from 1996 to be exact, which might be strange for those of you who know me as someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to drive. Actually, I still don&amp;rsquo;t really like to drive, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had lots of practice by now. In the time since I&amp;rsquo;ve bought my car I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty much to most places I visited before, but this time I had the chance to enjoy the drive there and stop whenever and wherever I wanted to. The roads here are strange though. While I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a strong dislike for gravel roads, it&amp;rsquo;s actually the highways that are the weirdest. When I hear the term highway I assume the kind of road that would imply in The Netherlands. Not here. Here a highway is 2 lanes (one for each direction), a maximum speed of 100 km/h but there will be bends that have recommended speeds of as low as 25 km/h. There are passing lanes in case the road is busy (not very often) or has so many bends you can&amp;rsquo;t see what&amp;rsquo;s coming from the other direction (very often). Of course, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget to mention the numerous one lane bridges that liven up the road, or the towns it goes through. Despite all this, the views those strange roads bring you too are worth having to put up with the constant roadworks and all the other things I mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the reason I bought this car is that I can actually sleep in it as well. So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of camping which can lead to some beautiful sights when waking up in the morning, and some terrible rain when trying to set it up for sleeping. And yes, it sleeps two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beautiful-places:230c8bf5dc0a96da5bf7e86382b0da14&#34;&gt;Beautiful places&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The South Island is full of beautiful places. From the fjords in Milford and Doubtful Sound, to the glaciers at Franz Josef and Fox. From the beaches and forests in Abel Tasman and Stewart Island to the lakes at Wanaka and Tekapo. The mountains that split the island in an east and west part have their own beauty as have the plains in other parts. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful country, so below are some of the photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken in my time here. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably add more to this album at a later date, but this is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/merry-christmas</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 07:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/merry-christmas</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC03186.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Merry Hawaiian Christmas&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC03186-768x1024.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Merry Hawaiian Christmas&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, finally an update and it&amp;rsquo;s only something in which I wish you a merry Christmas. Well, unfortunately you can&amp;rsquo;t have everything. A lot of stuff has happened in the past weeks, including bungy jumping, skydiving, rafting, jetboats, canyoning, even renting a car (don&amp;rsquo;t worry, New Zealand survived that), and even earthquakes (luckily no casualties).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this (or at least the interesting parts about it) will be mentioned in some blog posts that I&amp;rsquo;ll write once I actually take the time to do so. Just rest assured that I&amp;rsquo;m having a great time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Christmas, so far it&amp;rsquo;s been going good. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m full from the barbecue we had here at the hostel, where the hostel provided the meat and everybody else was supposed to make something like a salad or desert. This led to some nice (and some less nice) but all interesting dishes. So, all in all Dunedin seems like a nice place to celebrate Christmas. Also, with the good weather it&amp;rsquo;s a bit different from Lapland last year&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at this for now and just finish with wishing you all once again a Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milford Sound</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/milford-sound</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 23:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/milford-sound</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;02-12 until 05-12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milford Sound, New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s most famous tourist destination. It&amp;rsquo;s supposedly the most beautiful fjord in the country, and with a population of about 170 people (who are pretty much all working in the tourist trade) and up to a million visitors a year I don&amp;rsquo;t think there are many places in the world with a higher native to tourist ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-1.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Mirror Lakes&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-1-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Mirror Lakes&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I too wanted to go here to see how beautiful it actually is. And yes, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty impressive to see the mountains rising from the sea level. On the one hand I was really lucky with the weather, having had two days of hot sunshine after a couple of days that were mostly cloudy. To be honest though, I&amp;rsquo;d hoped for rain. Not because I like walking around in the rain so much, but because a good rainstorm in Milford Sound creates thousands of temporary waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, to be honest, there was a rainstorm for a couple of hours on my second evening there, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t on the water at that time so couldn&amp;rsquo;t really see all that much and when I went kayaking the next morning everything had dried up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-2.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;The Chasm&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-2-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Chasm&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is there to say about Milford Sound? First of all, if you have the chance go visit it. The fjord itself is pretty beautiful, but the road from Te Anau to Milford (the only way you can drive there) has some really beautiful sights. I would also recommend to take your own car if you do so. While it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have the extra information a bus driver will give you like &amp;ldquo;On this farm they were filming parts of The Hobbit last week&amp;rdquo; (aka you missed it) the chance to stop wherever you want is too nice not to do it. Places like the Mirror Lakes and The Chasm you&amp;rsquo;ll stop at even when you&amp;rsquo;re going by bus, but a lot of other nice places are simply passed by because there is a schedule that has to be kept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the driver was kind enough to stop at the Milford Sound Lodge so I and a couple of others could get off, I started with just some walking around the town. Well, it really was small, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much walking to be done directly around it. But that was ok, I could still relax and do all the planning for cruises and kayaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fullwidth&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-15.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Panorama of Milford Sound&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-15-1024x400.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Panorama of Milford Sound&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, on that first day, one thing you&amp;rsquo;ll immediately learn is that while there are a lot of tourists, that amount is nothing compared to the number of sandflies. It&amp;rsquo;s in fact so bad, that the Mauri had a legend about it. Apparently after Milford Sound was created by Maui, the goddes Hinenui-te-Po released the sandflies there in order to prevent it from becoming a paradise where humanity would linger for too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, trust me on this. Even covered in insect repellent you don&amp;rsquo;t want to stay in one place for very long while you&amp;rsquo;re there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-04.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Mountains rising from the sea&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-04-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Mountains rising from the sea&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my second day, or first full day actually, I went on a cruise. As the wind was really picking up around that time it was a lot of fun. Standing on top of the boat there were places where it was difficult to remain upright, but that only added to the fun. It was beautiful to see all of this. A lot of it was just like Doubtful Sound, with the mountains rising from the water and the various seals and penguins. Unfortunately here I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see any dolphins either, although cruises on the next day did get to see some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-08.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Black corral as seen in the underwater observatory&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-08-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Black corral as seen in the underwater observatory&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this was all fun, and part of the cruise was also to go to the Discovery Center, a floating underwater observatory. Because of the unique ecology of Milford Sound, where fresh (but very dark) water lies on top of the heavier salt water, there are many sea creatures that live at a far higher depth than usually. Say, at 10 to 15 meters instead of 100 meters. Among these is black corral. Of course, despite the name it&amp;rsquo;s white while still alive, in case the picture to the right confuses you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-11.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Kayaking&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/Milford-Sound-11-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Kayaking&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a fun cruise, and even more fun to come as the next day I went kayaking. It started at 7:15 in the morning, so I had to get up pretty early. Once pretty much awake, I got to dress up in a lovely outfit (as can be seen in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/hawaiian-shirts/&#34; title=&#34;Hawaiian shirts&#34;&gt;Hawaiian shirt photo&lt;/a&gt; of 4-12-2011) and we got into our two-person kayaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in a kayak with a guy from Belgium, so that worked out fine. Anyway, the weather had cleared up incredibly by now, and we enjoyed a very sunny day where we got to see everything up close including some more of the wildlife. Of course, not everybody was lucky as one couple dropped one of their cameras (a go pro that takes pictures every so often) into the water. As it was the second one they lost in 3 days, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing they&amp;rsquo;re going to give up on those.
So, the kayaking lasted until about 12:30 orso, and the rest of my time in Milford consisted mostly of relaxing so there isn&amp;rsquo;t really anything more to say about it. In short, I really enjoyed my time in Milford Sound.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Kepler track</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/doing-the-kepler-track</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 04:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/doing-the-kepler-track</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;25-11 until 28-11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kepler track is a 60 km circular track near Te Anau. It goes over a wide variety of landscapes; from mountains to marshes.
Not having learned my lesson from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/24/stewart-island-new-zealands-third-island/&#34; title=&#34;Stewart Island, New Zealand’s third island&#34;&gt;Stewart Island&lt;/a&gt;, I pretty much believed the walking times that were stated by the DOC (Department Of Conservation) and so booked a night in each of the three available huts. So I was going to do the track in 4 days. Maybe the Kepler Challenge where people do it in one day should have told me something about how much time it would actually take to do each day though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02364.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Protect the kiwis!&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02364-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Protect the kiwis!&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it was a great walk. An easy walk, but great. I also was very lucky with regard to the weather as I had three days of sunshine and only on the last day did it actually rain. This all led to some amazing views on the mountain tops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning of the track. The Kepler track goes through a national park so there&amp;rsquo;s all the usual warnings about dogs, poison, and traps to catch all the unwanted animals. Once you&amp;rsquo;re past this though, you start by walking through the trees for about an hour until you reach Brod Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02368.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Brod Bay&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02368-1024x400.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Brod Bay&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started quite late, I left the hostel at about 9:30 and had to walk about an hour to the track, this was the point where I first passed some people. That sounds worse than it is, as they started at another point on the track which made it a lot easier to do it in three days. I probably should&amp;rsquo;ve done some more research before deciding to walk it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the next couple of hours were a steady climb to the treeline, and when I finally reached that I really noticed the way the wind had picked up. Later I would hear that there were gusts of about 90 km/h, and I can tell you that didn&amp;rsquo;t fill me with confidence about walking along the mountain ridges the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02388.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Luxmore Hut&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02388-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Luxmore Hut&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily from the treeline it was only about half an hour to get to Luxmore Hut where I would staying the night. After several hours of hearing the hut creaking the wind calmed down, and I went out to visit the cave that was close by. This was a lot of fun to visit, as it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a path or anything. I actually had to climb and wind my way through everything in there. That also made the warnings pretty obvious (you had to bring at least two sources of light and tell someone you were going). Lots of fun, but not very good for photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02442.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Snow covered track&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02442-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Snow covered track&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was the day I got to walk along the mountain ridges. There were several sidetrips here as well, leading to either the summit of Mount Luxmore (1472 meters) or an observation point. Most interesting though was the snow that was still in places on the track. Normally I don&amp;rsquo;t mind snow so much, but I have to admit that when it&amp;rsquo;s on a 30 cm wide path with a steep slope down on one side I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy about having to cross it. Still, the views from up there were incredible. It isn&amp;rsquo;t even all that high but the shape of the mountains around you gives the impression it&amp;rsquo;s a lot higher than it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02462.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;View from the mountains&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02462-1024x400.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;View from the mountains&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after walking over and along the mountains for a couple of hours it was time to start descending again. This was probably the hardest part of the whole track, and the only time I (and everybody else I talked to) needed the estimated time. It was a two hour climb down, and that was pretty hard on the knees. And after the first hour, at which point I was under the treeline again, I started looking for the hut behind every corner. So, when I finally did reach Iris Burn hut I was pretty happy. And as there was a nice river nearby, I went for a short swim. The water wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that cold, but unfortunately there were once again a lot of sandflies around so after the swim I had to get dressed pretty quickly or end up being eaten alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done so the day before, the next day I started with a visit to Iris Burn Fall, a nice waterfall about 20 minutes from the hut. As the day&amp;rsquo;s walk was going to be pretty easy anyway, there was no rush. Once on the track I quickly caught up with trampers who left earlier and about halfway through I continued walking in a slower pace with some of them. Naturally, after walking for some hours and ending up at a lake, it was a good idea to swim again, so I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day was pretty much the same though. Except that this time there were some other views. The Big Slip for example is a big area that was washed away in 1984, so there are no big trees there or anything. And of course, walking through the marshes was a fun experience. While these weren&amp;rsquo;t the actual ones used for filming the Dead Marshes scenes in Lord of the Rings, they are exactly the same and located not far from them. Still, while I could probably have walked the whole track in two days, it was also fun to take the time and just relax on those sunny days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubtful Sound</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/doubtful-sound</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/12/doubtful-sound</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doubtful Sound is a fjord in Fiordland, New Zealand, named Doubtful by captain Cook who doubted he could sail in it. Of course, all of that and more can be read on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doubtful_Sound&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to repeat it here.  I&amp;rsquo;ll just say what I did while there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get some luxury for a change, or at least luxury compared to staying in hostels, I went on an overnight cruise. This meant that in the morning I was picked up at my hostel by a bus taking me to Lake Manapouri. We were then transferred across Lake Manapouri on a boat going all the way to the power station there. Apparently, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this before, Lake Te Anau, Lake Manapouri and Doubtful Sound are all connected to work as a hydro power plant, but one that is  ecologically friendly (read: the lakes weren&amp;rsquo;t raised but have to stay within their natural limits).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02116.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;View along the way to Doubtful Sonud&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02116-225x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;View along the way to Doubtful Sonud&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, from there it was yet another bus ride, along some pretty awesome views and some really steep declines where the bus went really slow in order not to have anything happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the end, we arrived at the wharf where we were met by the ship that would be our home for the next 24 hours. So, after all the mandatory safety briefings and being pointed to our cabins (a small room I had to share with three others), we could have a look around while we were sailing through Doubtful Sound. I have to admit, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty impressive to see all of these mountains just rise out of the sea. In places it was pretty much a wall that went straight up into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing this for a couple of hours, we ended up in one of the arms of the fjord where the water activities were to take place. There was the choice to go kayaking, or be carried along in a motorboat. Anyway, the kayaking was fun, even though I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real experience with it so I didn&amp;rsquo;t go very fast. Of course, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the slowest person either but at times it was a bit frustrating to see so many people passing me by. Anyway, it was fun, and gave a good opportunity to get close to everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02160.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Mountains rising from the sea&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02160-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Mountains rising from the sea&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the kayaking, there was an option to go swimming. Well, basically it was diving off the ship into the cold water. Or not very warm water actually. Despite the fact that the top couple of meters of the fjord are actually fresh water, straight from the mountains that get over 7 meters of rain a year, it was warmer than the water around Stewart Island had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t sunny as it had been there, so a hot shower was very welcome afterwards. Unfortunately, as my normal pants had gotten wet during the kayaking (silly mistake for not wearing my swimming gear than as well), I spent the rest of the day walking around in my swimming pants. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad though, they dried up fairly quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this entertainment though we went in the direction of the sea, where we had the chance to once again spot some fur seals and yellow-crested penguins. It&amp;rsquo;s always fun to see those, so that was cool. It was also immediately noticeable that the sea was a lot wilder than the fjord itself. But not too wild to go slightly in there luckily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t all that much else to tell about that first day though. We had a very nice dinner (buffet), and after that the nature guide, who had already given a lot of information all day, gave a presentation about the nature there. In the meantime the ship had moved to yet another arm of the fjord where we moored for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02331.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;More mountains and waterfalls&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/12/DSC02331-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;More mountains and waterfalls&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was really wet though. It had started raining in the evening, and at one point I heard that there had been about 120 mm of rain in the past 24 hours, which meant that all the waterfalls were going to be even more impressive on the way back. After an early breakfast (7 am) we were underway again back to the start of Doubtful Sound. We did have a short extra stop though in one of the arms where we did a so-called &amp;ldquo;Sound of Silence&amp;rdquo; thing. This was basically that no sounds were made (even the ship&amp;rsquo;s engines were turned off) and we could all enjoy the sound of the waterfalls around us there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I have to say it was really nice and impressive to go through Doubtful Sound. Below are some more of the pictures I took there, not all 243 though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stewart Island, New Zealand&#39;s third island</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/stewart-island-new-zealands-third-island</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 05:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/stewart-island-new-zealands-third-island</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;12-11-2011 until 17-11-2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to say about the first two days I spent in Invercargill (the first day I enjoyed the sun in the park, and the second day I did laundry and other stuff while it was raining), this post is about my time on Stewart Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewart Island, or Rakiura, is seen by many as New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s third island as it&amp;rsquo;s the biggest island outside of the North Island and South Island. More info on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stewart_Island&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. Still, with a population of about 400 people and 85% of the island being a national preserve, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much in the way of infrastructure. But there is a lot of nature, and that was my reason for going there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most southern points in the world, and thereby pretty close to Antarctica, and one of the places with the highest possibility of seeing a kiwi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect Vodafone not to work on the island at all, or I would have given a bit more of a heads-up that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be reachable for a while. And with internet available at the friendly rate of only 2 dollars per 15 minutes, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like using a Windows pc to give any updates either.
So, what was there to do on Stewart Island?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oban-and-surroundings:33ffa93fc62aa358d651e63f4d25d13b&#34;&gt;Oban and surroundings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01740.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Ryan’s Creek&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01740-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Ryan’s Creek&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oban is the big town on the island. It&amp;rsquo;s where you arrive with the ferry and it has at least 4 streets. But to be honest, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to do except do some walking around. So, when I arrived I checked with the Department of Conservation, to see what walks were possible. As one of them went past something called Ryan&amp;rsquo;s creek, that was my first target. After all, Ryan never told me he had a creek named after him so I had to see this for myself. This walk was pretty nice, and once I&amp;rsquo;d finished it I didn&amp;rsquo;t return to the town, but just started on the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01945.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Friendly people everywhere&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01945-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Friendly people everywhere&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pretty much continued this way, exploring what there was to see around Oban itself, until I could start on the Rakiura track itself. The tracks differed from half an hour, to half a day (at least according to the planning, but I suspect that was based on people who walked around with two broken legs). Basically it was a lot of fun to just walk around, and everybody was really friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is a bit of a tourist area, so they took some precautions. But hey, ignore a warning at your own risk, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rakiura-track:33ffa93fc62aa358d651e63f4d25d13b&#34;&gt;Rakiura track&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rakiura track is one of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s so called Great Tracks. This was a three day walk around part of the island, and I felt like doing it to see how things would go. Of course, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect to like the walking so much that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I want to do all 9 Great Tracks (one of which is actually by kayak). However, I&amp;rsquo;m getting ahead of myself, so let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The track is a 3 day hike through parts of the island you can only reach following this track. There&amp;rsquo;s actually a larger, 12-day track around the entire island as well, but that was too much for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01863.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Chain to the South Island&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01863-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Chain to the South Island&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of the track was around the west coast, to a hut at Port William. The route started by going over the streets, but after about 4 kilometers I could turn onto the walking track, where I passed under the symbolical chain that connects Stewart Island to the &amp;ldquo;mainland&amp;rdquo; of the South Island. Walking past this I encountered many beautiful sights of the sea and was able to hear birds all around me the whole time. Often hearing was as often as I could come though, let alone being quick enough to get my camera. Still, this was pretty amazing. It was also a nice and easy walk with perfect weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 4 hours I&amp;rsquo;d reached the hut. This was time spent relaxing on some of the beaches (read trying to outrun the sandflies) and talking to an American who was walking part of the track. I&amp;rsquo;d met him earlier in Dunedin, so it was fun to meet him again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01901.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Beach at Port William&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01901-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Beach at Port William&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving at Port William, I met a couple who were only there for lunch, but they&amp;rsquo;d gone swimming earlier and while the water was cold, it was supposedly nice and refreshing. Of course, hearing that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist and went for a swim myself. And indeed, there you notice exactly how close it is to Antarctica. The water was freezing. Still, fun though and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see water that is so clear that you can see the bottom everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on more people arrived, and we talked a bit. When it became dark though they all went to bed. Personally I figured that I had no idea when I&amp;rsquo;d have a clear sky again so far removed from any light sources, so I wanted to look at the stars for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was really amazing. I don&amp;rsquo;t have pictures of it, but my first reaction was the quote from 2001 - A Space Odyssey: &amp;ldquo;Oh my god, it&amp;rsquo;s full of stars.&amp;rdquo;
Unfortunately, after not too long the sandflies drove me inside as well. Rain was predicted for the next two days that I&amp;rsquo;d be walking, but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t start until the afternoon. As there was a bit of a climb on the second day I decided to leave pretty early so I&amp;rsquo;d be past that before the rain would start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I succeeded in this, leaving around 9:30. The track was also a lot faster to walk than the 6 hours that were estimated, in the end taking me about 4.5 hours, which included two 15 minute stops. Once to take pictures (including a Hawaiian shirt one) and once to put on my wet weather gear. It started to be a bit muddy as well around the time it started raining, which made for a far slippier route than I really liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01912.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Abandoned Log Hauler&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01912-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Abandoned Log Hauler&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that first stop was at the location of two abandoned log haulers. When the milling stopped there, these two were left behind for reasons unknown. It&amp;rsquo;s rather weird to see two of these big machines in an area where there is only nature everywhere around. But, I still had far to go at that time, so I quickly went on to do the &amp;ldquo;climbing&amp;rdquo; that was needed. Basically one big stairway to the top of a small mountain or even large hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As said, this went all pretty well and there was a lot of forest to see everywhere around me as I walked. Of course, you couldn&amp;rsquo;t see far at all, and so I really had no idea where I was except that I&amp;rsquo;d passed the high climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01925.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Bunks at North Arm Hut&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01925-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bunks at North Arm Hut&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after being rained on for a while (but it being dry again) I finally reached the North Arm Hut, my sleeping place for the night. Just to give people an impression though of the comfort in one of those huts where it comes to sleeping, I&amp;rsquo;ll refer you to the picture on the left. It&amp;rsquo;s more cramped than in a hostel, and for those who&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure to sleep on the TU-noob boat it smells like the sleeping compartment there. Still, as it was pretty quiet on the track I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually have to sleep next to anyone so that was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This night, four of the people from last night stayed in this hut as well. These were two Czech exchange students, Alex and Magda, and a Polish couple, Thomas and Kasha. It was pretty fun to talk to them again, and as they were walking slower I could also see how wet I would&amp;rsquo;ve been if I&amp;rsquo;d stayed outside for longer. (Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see other people enter miserably wet by the time you&amp;rsquo;re dry again.) There was also a group of kiwi people who were being guided around the track, but walking the other way. They had the fun of telling us about the mud we would be encountering the next day. Well, that was mostly it for that day, as a short search for kiwi&amp;rsquo;s (the bird type) didn&amp;rsquo;t turn up anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01927.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Mud&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01927-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Mud&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day had two things to say for itself. One, unlike the predictions of even the guide the night before, it was dry and sunny. Two, there was a freakish amount of mud. At the time I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of this mud, as trying to get past it would often only make me fall down, which is not a fun experience while carrying a big pack. Nevertheless, looking back on it I can see that it was fun as well. Especially after I gave up on trying to avoid the mud and just splashed through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mud was only for the first 1.5 hours though, after that it became a lot better again and the environment just kept being incredibly beautiful all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/bayshotraikuratrail.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;A shot of a bay I can’t remember the name of right now&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/bayshotraikuratrail.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;A shot of a bay I can’t remember the name of right now&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ulva-island:33ffa93fc62aa358d651e63f4d25d13b&#34;&gt;Ulva Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01978.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Bird on Ulva Island&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01978-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bird on Ulva Island&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the Raikura trail, I stayed another day so I could visit Ulva Island the next morning. Ulva Island is an island in one of the bays of Stewart Island (so basically, on island of an island of an island), but is made completely free of non-indigenous species. So, only true New Zealand animals live there. This means it&amp;rsquo;s one of the places where you can get the closest to how New Zealand was before humanity arrived. There&amp;rsquo;s an amazing number of birds on the island and it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful to watch these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As before though, either I&amp;rsquo;m a really bad photographer without any patience, or it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly hard to get a good photo of all the birds that are around there. My guess is actually a combination of the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-the-south-island:33ffa93fc62aa358d651e63f4d25d13b&#34;&gt;Back to the South Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather had a turn for the worst by the time I was going to leave. The ferry after mine was actually cancelled, and there were some pretty impressive waves. Of course, on a boat there are always some people who enjoy this, (three including me), and a number who can&amp;rsquo;t handle it. Barf bags were available for them though. The photo below doesn&amp;rsquo;t do it any justice though, but I&amp;rsquo;ll see if in the future I can arrange for one of the movies I made of it to be uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;centered&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/obantobluff.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;The weather from Oban to Bluff&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/obantobluff.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The weather from Oban to Bluff&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunedin and the Otega Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/dunedin-and-the-otega-peninsula</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 23:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/dunedin-and-the-otega-peninsula</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;03-11-2011 - 09-11-2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally another blog post! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last wrote something, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just get straight to it. This is about the time I spent in Dunedin. I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t do much there, mostly some relaxing, as the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that great. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s also more to the south so that makes sense.
Anyway, I took the bus from Christchurch (had to walk really fast to catch it as I was a bit late) and after about 6 hours I ended up in Dunedin. My first reaction was that it was cold. I was still walking around in only a t-shirt and that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the kind of clothing you&amp;rsquo;d want to wear there. The second reaction, once I started walking to the hostel, was that there are a lot of hills. Anyway, this was fine and after a short walk I ended up at Hogwartz. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s named after Harry Potter and there were a couple of rooms with a similar name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as I arrived in the evening I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much and went to bed pretty early. The second day I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much either, mostly just walking around the city center a bit and seeing what there was to do over there. Dunedin is pretty much a student city and that&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear from what there is to do in the city. Aside from some museums and the like the city itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01311.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Fin whale in Otago Museum&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01311-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fin whale in Otago Museum&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third day, after hearing there was actually snow in the hills around the center of the city, I decided to go visit the Otago museum. The museum was pretty interesting. Not only did it show the history of the entire peninsula since humans arrived (first the Maori, and later Europeans), but it went back all the way to the time of the dinosaurs and also explained the sea/ocean critters that were there back then and the ones that are still around. Of course, a lot of animals are now extinct, and the woods that used to cover over 80% of the area have been reduced to only 20% in order to make place for all the sheep. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s really interesting to see how different the wildlife is in New Zealand. It&amp;rsquo;s not often you find a country of this size that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have, and never really had, any animals that are dangerous to humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the museum I took a visit to the botanic gardens, which is of course always fun. There&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of beautiful plants and trees to see in a place like that, but I actually wanted to enjoy some of the real nature around there. So I booked a tour for the next day that would take me up to the more secluded parts of the Otago Peninsula and where I would be able to see some of the rarer animals around here, like yellow-eyed penguins and the royal albatross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour started with a visit to the Albatross Center, which is at the only mainland colony of albatrosses in the world. As these also happened to be the biggest ones around this was quite a lot of fun and I learned quite a bit about them. Such as the fact that after they&amp;rsquo;re old enough to leave the nest they go to fly around the world for another four years until they come back again to the exact spot where they were born in order to find a mate. The courtship than takes another four years, in which the two will only meet at their yearly get together in the colony. In between the couple of months they stay there they&amp;rsquo;ll fly around the world some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this we went to a secluded beach where we had the chance to see the penguins returning home and the sea lions that were lying on the beach. Sea lions actually don&amp;rsquo;t do much apparently once they&amp;rsquo;re older, so only the young ones were active when we got closer. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t get too close though as apparently they like to play a lot. And for young sea lions playing involves a lot of biting. As they can run about 20 km/h on the beach (which isn&amp;rsquo;t really slower than a regular human) you might not want to provoke them into actually doing that. As for the penguins, they were mostly busy with their eggs or walking home after their hunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last stop was on a rocky beach on the other side of a hill where we got to see some fur seals. As there were still young ones around them this was pretty cute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I again didn&amp;rsquo;t do much except decide where I wanted to go. Eventually I decided on Invercargill in order to go to Stewart Island from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01651.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Beer tasting at Speight’s brewery&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/DSC01651-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Beer tasting at Speight’s brewery&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my last full day in Dunedin I decided to go visit the Speight&amp;rsquo;s brewery, which is the beer you can buy everywhere around here and as it&amp;rsquo;s home is in Dunedin that seemed like a good thing to visit. All of the beer they create at the moment is actually done in Dunedin as the only other facility they had was in Christchurch, but didn&amp;rsquo;t survive the earthquakes intact. Naturally a tour of a brewery ends with a chance to taste beers, so despite the fact that I only went for the cultural value I had to try all six beers they offered for this. One of the interesting things about the brewery is that they offer for free the same spring water they use for their beers. This can be gotten from a tap outside of the brewery and there&amp;rsquo;s pretty much always a line there of locals who prefer this fresh and clean water over the stuff they get at home. This leads up to over a million liters of water a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there ends my tale about Dunedin. The next day was only waiting for the bus to arrive that brought me to Invercargill so that isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly interesting to talk about. Aside from this there was of course the usual talking to other travelers, including meeting the Indian guys from Christchurch again, but that&amp;rsquo;s all to be expected and I won&amp;rsquo;t bother you with things like that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akaroa</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/akaroa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2011/11/akaroa</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I&amp;rsquo;d decided that enough time had been spent in Christchurch for now, I looked where I wanted to go and decided that Akaroa would be a good start. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about it except that there was some nice nature there and you could see/swim with dolphins. All in all, interesting enough to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the evening before I left I booked a seat on the shuttle there and was ready the next morning to be picked up. On the way there we had some stops, in a small town called Little River and later at a place called Hilltop which offered a great view of Akaroa Harbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fullwidth&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/Akaroa-4448.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Akaroa Harbour seen from Hilltop&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/Akaroa-4448.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Akaroa Harbour seen from Hilltop&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving in Akaroa itself, a town that is basically one or two streets along the beach, we stopped next to the harbor. Once again following the first things first principle I and the only other backpacker on the shuttle (a German girl named Anja) went to check on the times for doing the whole swimming with dolphins thing. Which was pretty much immediately, actually 10 minutes ago. Very well, we&amp;rsquo;d left our backpacks in the shuttle where we could pick them up later in the afternoon so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem. So, we quickly put on the provided wetsuits and after the necessary instructions we were on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/BCAK111011066240.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Me with a Hector dolphin&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/BCAK111011066240-300x200.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Me with a Hector dolphin&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was great, so that helped a lot in making it more fun. Anyway, we moved into the harbor and after finding a pod of dolphins went into the water. It was a lot more fun to actually do this than I expected. It&amp;rsquo;s really strange to see so many dolphins swimming around you, even though it was a bit hard to see them clearly without my glasses. We stayed in the water for about 45 minutes, which is apparently the maximum allowed time to spent with a single pod of dolphins. A big reason for this is because Hector dolphins are an endangered species, about as rare as a Bengal tiger or Silverback Gorilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After returning from the swim it was time to look for a place to spend the night. After all, you didn&amp;rsquo;t really expect that I would have arranged that beforehand, now did you? Unfortunately, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as I expected. The hostels in Akaroa were pretty much full, but eventually we found a place to stay in a nearby town at the Okunu Farm Hostel. This was a 20 minute drive from Akaroa, so luckily we were picked up. This was a nice hostel to stay, and really quiet. I understood that once the season really starts it will be a lot busier though, but I can recommend staying there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/Akaroa-08.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Cloudy morning in Okunu&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2011/11/Akaroa-08-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cloudy morning in Okunu&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening was mostly spent talking and playing games with a couple of Taiwanese girls, and for the morning Anja and I decided to do some walking in the hills. Of course, that morning the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as it was the day before, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop us from going anyway. The views were really great from up there, although at some points the actual path to travel was less so due to a bit of rain that had fallen during the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, not much else to say about this. After the walk we asked for a drive back to Akaroa where we would then take the shuttle back to Christchurch. During the bus ride we visited a cheese factory and stopped at a small beach, but not much else. We did have the pleasure of having to arrange a place to sleep as Christchurch was getting fully booked by now. Eventually we did find a place, which was good. Unfortunately it was a place where they had a fat cat as pet, which my allergies didn&amp;rsquo;t think was good. Oh well, I survived and it was only for a single night anyway as after that I left for Dunedin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>