<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Australia on Arjen&#39;s travels</title>
    <link>https://www.arjen.eu/countries/australia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Australia on Arjen&#39;s travels</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 22:38:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.arjen.eu/countries/australia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A year of Aussies</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2013/07/a-year-of-aussies</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 22:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2013/07/a-year-of-aussies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today it&amp;rsquo;s been a year since I arrived in Australia. In fact, yesterday marked the day that my visa expired and would have had to leave the country. If I was still using that same visa that is. Which I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I have a so-called 457 or &lt;em&gt;Temporary Business Entry (Class UC) Work (Skilled) (Subclass 457)&lt;/em&gt; visa now for Australia. Regardless of the strange bureaucratic behaviour of using a crazy name and then only focusing on the number, this means that I (and Kelsey as she was the secondary applicant on it) can stay here for 4 years as long as there is a company sponsoring me. Obviously that&amp;rsquo;s the case right now, as I&amp;rsquo;m still working at the great &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evolution7.com.au&#34;&gt;Evolution 7&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why have I decided to stay here in Melbourne? First of all, I have to admit there is a limit to how long I can do the backpacking thing without getting bored and tired of living out of a suitcase. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m getting old, or just got fed up with that lifestyle. Either way, I wanted to have a place to call home again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;fullwidth&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/08/OperaHouse.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Sydney Opera House&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/08/OperaHouse.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Sydney Opera House&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain why I want to stay here in Melbourne, Australia instead of coming back to The Netherlands. Mostly it&amp;rsquo;s because I feel like it. Melbourne is a great city to live in, and in many ways actually reminds me of Amsterdam. Not completely of course, for example there aren&amp;rsquo;t any canals around here and Melbourne has 4 times as many people living in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big factor is that while I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like backpacking continuously anymore, I do still want to keep exploring and Australia is perfectly situated for that. First of all, there are big parts of this huge country I haven&amp;rsquo;t even come close to. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve only seen the east coast and Tasmania which leaves about 90% of the country. Sure, most of it is like a desert but there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of interesting stuff as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good as a gateway into Asia. Flights from here into Asia are cheap and often on special so there&amp;rsquo;s a good opportunity to explore there a couple of weeks at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of traveling, while I&amp;rsquo;m staying here that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won&amp;rsquo;t be visiting The Netherlands. As a matter of fact, I&amp;rsquo;ll be heading there very soon. As in one month from now soon. In September Kelsey and I will be catching up with our families and friends. First we&amp;rsquo;ll go to The Netherlands for about 3 weeks, and this will be followed by Hong Kong. To make things easier for everyone, at the bottom of this post are our flight plans, as always times are in the local time of the airport/city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened since I&amp;rsquo;ve left The Netherlands, most notable for me increases in the family with the births of both my nephew Jesse and my cousin&amp;rsquo;s baby girl Jasmijn as well as my other cousin getting married today (Congratulations Eelco and Krista!). So, despite saying how much I like it here I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to catching up with both family and friends in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To The Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight QF29, Qantas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Melbourne, Sunday September 1 09:45&lt;br /&gt;
To: Hong Kong, Sunday September 1 17:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight 4121, Etihad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Hong Kong, Monday September 2 18:55&lt;br /&gt;
To: Abu Dhabi, Monday September 2 23:25&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight 7308, KLM flying for Etihad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Abu Dhabi, Tuesday September 3 01:55&lt;br /&gt;
To: Amsterdam, Tuesday September 3 07:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Hong Kong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight 7307, KLM flying for Etihad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Amsterdam, Sunday September 22 11:35&lt;br /&gt;
To: Abu Dhabi, Sunday September 22 20:05&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight 4122, Etihad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Abu Dhabi, Sunday September 22 21:40&lt;br /&gt;
To: Hong Kong, Monday September 23 09:40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to Melbourne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight QF128&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Hong Kong, Friday October 4 20:15&lt;br /&gt;
To: Sydney, Saturday October 5 07:25&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight QF419&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From: Sydney, Saturday October 5 09:00&lt;br /&gt;
To: Melbourne, Saturday October 5 10:35&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on the road in Tasmania</title>
      <link>https://www.arjen.eu/2013/04/back-on-the-road-in-tasmania</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 12:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.arjen.eu/2013/04/back-on-the-road-in-tasmania</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this blog, and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to jump forward to the present time. I&amp;rsquo;ll post about all the earlier happenings as well, but for now I suspect it&amp;rsquo;s more interesting to know what I&amp;rsquo;m up to at the moment. So, without further ado, here&amp;rsquo;s a short post about Tasmania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasmania:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;Tasmania&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/tasmaniamap.png&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Map of Tasmania&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/tasmaniamap-300x285.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Map of Tasmania&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 7 months we (Kelsey and myself) have mostly spent our time in Melbourne. There were some short trips at various times, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t been really traveling since we got to Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that has changed, and on the 18th of March 2013 we set off for the beautiful island of Tasmania where we would stay until the 26th. During this time I drove the car we rented. The rental company generously called it a camper van, but with a low roof. Another description could be a pimped SUV. Either way, it was a good car to drive, allowed us to sleep in it and in general served us well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-oyster-bay:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;The Great Oyster Bay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09751.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Wineglass Bay&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09751-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Wineglass Bay&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first big stop on this trip was the Great Oyster Bay, and the connected Freycinet National Park. The bay itself was beautiful, and when we arrived there on the 19th we had a quiet evening. The next day however we went for a walk to Wineglass Bay. This is a beautiful bay inside the national park. It was a very pleasant walk on a beautiful day. Aside from the environment though, the wildlife was well-represented by wallabies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09791.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Petting a wallaby at Wineglass Bay&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09791-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Petting a wallaby at Wineglass Bay&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally got to the beach, we had a bit of lunch there and were joined for this by one of these wallabies. Despite it&amp;rsquo;s wishes, we obviously weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to feed it (or felt the need to do so) but it stayed around for a long time anyway and even allowed people to pet it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bay-of-fires:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;The Bay of Fires&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09842.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;The Bay of Fires&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09842-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The Bay of Fires&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went north, up to the Bay of Fires. Unfortunately, it was raining so we couldn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy long walks along the shore. Nevertheless, it was fun to see the red rocks that (I assume) gives the place it&amp;rsquo;s name. After we left the bay we stopped for a bit at a quite beautiful waterfall named the St Columba Falls before we finally set up camp in the rain. I have to admit that while it&amp;rsquo;s part of the whole camping experience I&amp;rsquo;m not a great fan of the whole rain thing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;narawntapu-national-park:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;Narawntapu National Park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09874.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Narawntapu&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09874-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Narawntapu&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily the weather cleared up a bit on the next day, so we could get underway with good weather again. Not that we did a lot of interesting things during the day as we visited Launceston and did quite a fair bit of driving. Of course, there were some short stops along the way as well, but nothing really interesting. That night we stayed in a Narawntapu National Park though, and that was fun. Aside from having a parking space literally two steps from the beach, we were pretty much sleeping in between the wildlife as there were wallabies and wombats everywhere around after sunset. Unfortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t see any Tasmanian Devils, but it was really nice to see the others anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cradle-mountain:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;Cradle Mountain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;float-left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09931.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;set&#34; data-title=&#34;Cradle Mountain&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjen.eu/img/posts/2013/04/DSC09931-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Cradle Mountain&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of days later we ended up at Cradle Mountain, which is probably the most photographed place in Tasmania. Not that I&amp;rsquo;d actually heard about it before the plans for going to this state were solidified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, despite it once again raining when we got to the walking tracks we walked around Dove Lake, which is the lake in front of the mountain. As the weather cleared up during the day we got some beautiful sights anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rest-of-tasmania:7fa4cac2c7aa98e37311a58217c2859c&#34;&gt;The rest of Tasmania&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many more beautiful sights in Tasmania than the view I&amp;rsquo;ve described above, but I prefer to go with the idea of a picture being worth a thousand words instead so you can have a look at the gallery below for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all though, it was a lot of fun to drive around Tasmania and see all the wonderful nature it has. The roads themselves are twisting all the time, and for many of these there is a recommended driving speed of 25 km/h, but they offer some amazing views. That, and an incredible amount of roadkill; I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot more dead wallabies than live ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>